I'll start with this my German my team
nicaya 151 ping dupatta
party purification of Elms food
isn't like in the collection of Elms
food purification right practice so one
occasion the blessed one is living its
rajagaha then when it was evening the
Red Bull Sally Potter
rose from meditation went to the Blessed
One after paying homage to him he sat
down to one side and the Blessed One
then said to him Sally Potter your
faculties are clear the colour of your
skin is pure and bright
what abiding do you often abide in now
it applies now rentable so I often abide
in Sunita
emptiness is good good so he put a 9 d
Joe often you often abide in the abiding
of a great man for this is an abiding of
the great man so study put it if a
bhikkhu should wish may I now often
abide in emptiness he should consider
thus on the path by which I went to the
village for alms or in the place where I
wondered for Elms or on the part of
which I returned from the alms round was
there any desire lust hate delusion or a
version in my mind regarding forms
cognizable by the eye if so by if by
still reviewing he knows thus on the on
the path which I went to the village for
alms there was desire lust hate and delusion
there was desire lust hate and delusion
in my mind then he should make an effort
to abandon those evil unwholesome states
but if by reviewing he knows thus there
was no desire lust hate of delusion very
in my mind regarding forms the
cognizable by the eye and then he can't
abide happy and glad training night and
day in all some states with many
passages and see most people sort of
well I would assume you already know it
or do you just read over it but that
that's all a person needs to do the
truth that it's nothing it's not to keep
you beating but it so it's not it's not
a magical great mystical secret that
needs to be figured out for something
knows the experience that you have and
you know rising or bandaged in your body
and whatnot none of that is relevant
it's the discernment of greed aversion
delusion and then not having it no
delighting in it if he dies on its own
you're mindful of it until having a
reason it has to cease his own and
that's what it means he trains day and
night he doesn't go day and night then
repeats to himself touching touching
statements that been moving moving
sitting sitting
no he keeps reviewing the experience as
a whole
without an attentiveness and a step one
step two step three just keeps anar
keeps the peripheral vision as far as he
can see the background of his mind he's
the great easier version is it is there
an inclination to it creep is an
inclination to the diversion is a
conventional delusion and by delusion I
mean distraction many people don't even
understand what delusion is delusion is
but it's obviously not sensual and not
ill will but it's it's it's something
that results in loss of mindfulness and
by definition is faceback indolence
mental in the letters or choosing the
thing they will distract you from it
even if it's not unwholesome per se oh I
would like to win oh go ahead and talk
to white people and maybe meet with some
other monks
but it's rooted in just designed to
distract yourself from yourself and so
that's delusion that's why it's subtle
that's where the hardest one do because
it's it's not obviously and also so you
need to remove even even the slightest
sort of layers of bad faith they will
kind of make you believe that you're
really doing for good reasons what
really you're just doing it to distract
yourself from your mindfulness so that's
what it means he practices day and night
day night he keeps a watchful eye on the
on the horizon of his mind basically
what's coming if it's awesome if it's on
also if it's something awesome TV lights
he abides gladly and so on he enjoys and
he's quite happy and bright that because
he knows exactly what he needs to do and
he's doing it as opposed to getting all
caught up and wound up and intense not
knowing what he's doing and then using
everything and nothing at the same time
and then obviously just get tiny turn it
off and then your huge energy release
and then you think wow so powerful and
and still you notice that closer to
discerning the nature of greed aversion
delusions is it present am i fueling it am i
is it present am i fueling it am i
maintaining it am i entertaining it it
doesn't it doesn't say that see your
binds happy and glad training night and
day in house of states which is the
absence absence see that's all he's seen
at discerning the absence exactly so
he's discerning the absence of
unwholesome states and that is his
abiding and his meditation that is his
Samadhi that's resulting in Habana it
develop fully he doesn't listen a
wholesome and unwholesome and then he
goes and does some meditation technique
did you know helps him feel good with
something
but they and not now like half an hour
today from the morning he wakes up till
he goes to sleep he does not entertain
and he's not negligent know that you got
to everything just doing other things
that matter
things like greed aversion and delusion
things like wanting to dissent in a
sense of sort of delighting in it things
like aversion in a sense of rejecting
and trying to get rid of it and delusion
things that I'm trying to distract
himself from himself
so aversion is not only hate and obvious
hate a version is trying to get a
version is basically trying to get rid
of the spontaneously reason but sensual
thought thought of a beauty of a
beautiful object of sight sound smell
taste touch in itself as as a reason on
its own same excites come-come in the
area range of the eye thoughts come in
the range of the mind
that's not your doing not knowing that
it's not your doing you will be trying
to get rid of it you will be
overstepping the mark and that's a
version that's like that simile of
debate the deer herd suitor went with
the first first sees I'm sorry the
second hand sees the first heard are
they eat carelessly as in engaged
sensuality and because of that is
subjected to modest control but then
they shun the whole thing they don't
discern extent of Martyrs bait but they
say no to all of it and that's usually
the first response oh I must not I must
not do this I must not do this I must
not have this that's attacked me that's
attacked and everything sites are
attachments thoughts are attachments
possessions that everything is
attachment because you can't
differentiate so then you want to throw
all of it and it basically becomes
universim whenever these things arise
you overstep your mark and if
you're shunning it you and that's how
you get hooked because either way you
need to feel with it
so they're they're much subtle and
layers of aversion than just hatred and
irritation you can have a version in
regard to your own your own senses and
the objects that have appeared oh there
is the pressure of a beautiful object
the prospect of it and universe because
you you know you're afraid of the
consequences and everything else but
being afraid of consequence is one thing
but then actually giving in to the
aversion and then actively trying to
deny the thought get rid of it get rid
of it get you it is its roots in the
inversion so that's also an awesome and
because of that you keep engaging with
it yes sometimes the complete no you
know like mindfulness and the last
bastion of your hope is just not
breaking a virtue then yeah you just
have to do it and say no to it but
that's like you know maybe once every in
a while most more often than not people
actually just cultivate a version
unknowingly for thinking they must be
getting little result but they're not
you're not the one responsible for
debate it's the murder that sorta
doesn't see all the datasets of debate
no not a sense of debate sets of the
beautiful object and enticing objects
that make the make that they are
entrapped so you start discerning the
plate and then the Buddha says the final
deer her learns how to eat carefully so
they it around a bit because if you shun
debate you get caught if you canister
you get caught so you learn how to eat
carefully as in your mindful in regard
to that which can attract you when you
don't engage with it either through
delighting in it or already rejecting it
you discern to allow you learn how to
allow it in you having a reason you know
it will cease it's not your problem and
that's how matter cannot see you because
Mara can see you only when there is a
form of engagement in regard to the bait
that he sets up based on the engagement
he can gauge where you are look he
avoided in here but he didn't avoided
there he completely and carelessly or or
or he's trying to get rid of it he he's
still interfering with my bait so I know
he is there but in the final deer I've
came and is absolutely
food still there no interference but so
did they're not interfering in the sense
that they're trying to destroy the bait
get rid of it they don't interfere in a
sense they're trying to eat it but it
must be somewhere but Americans see them
now because there is no response in
regard to inciting objects any senses of
thoughts and that's how you go beyond
centrality as well
so back to the the emptiness it's not a
place of I could bubble no its absence
these things are absent and because what
he knows what's present well its absence
of certain things that's what your
auntie oh it's always a negative
reference emptiness definition of
emptiness again with the young you know
collection going he doesn't do if he
lives in the forest and live secluded he
goes amongst the people and then sees
he's mind gets the sepoys monk is angry
it gets distracted when he comes back in
that seclusion the impetus oh yeah no it
cannot be stressed sufficiently enough
the necessity physical seclusion as in
the actual physical seclusion when you
know there is not even a well what do
you know where there isn't an easy
prospect of people encroaching upon you
so you know most likely you've
physically removed don't like physical
seclusion go to your room when you close
your door and you surrounded but this
whole having to go into the village for
food there's there's your opportunity to
be around oh yeah sure sure sure
of course and that will give you more
than enough to leave you and it review
that there is nothing nothing puja
that's great
then you're gonna enjoy your seclusion
even more yeah